

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Rafael Gomes de Cresci

a +39 3518149400 **b** +44 7494925050

x cresci@outlook.com

Skype cresci | Google Hangouts cresci@gmail.com

Sex Male | Date of birth 26/02/1982 | Nationality Italian, Brazilian

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Multidisciplinary IT senior analyst specialized in datacenter infrastructure, systems and network administration and connectivity peering; along with an educational background in International Relations.

Available for relocation and work-related travel up to 100% of the time.

WORK EXPERIENCE

18/05/2019-Present

Senior Systems Administrator

iomart Group plc, Glasgow (United Kingdom)

Windows, Linux systems, Cisco Firewall, Microsoft Exchange/Office 365, mySQL and Microsoft SQL high availability, DellEMC storage, VMware vCenter and VDI administration, Barracuda Load Balancers, CentOS and RedHat Linux administration, managed patching, servers rack and stack, CAT5/6 and fiber cabling, datacenter access control, AWS cloud server maintenance and patching. on a Managed Hosting platform company top 3 in the United Kingdom.

01/07/2018-Present

Freelance Consultant

Task-specific Windows, Microsoft SQL Server, backup, vmware ESXi and Debian/CentOS Plesk server administration and short/overnight maintenance tasks for a small number of customers.

16/10/2017-30/06/2018

Alumnus

Apple Developer Academy, Napoli (Italy)

Academic year experience as a student

07/12/2015-10/10/2017

Server Build Technician III (Senior Datacenter Specialist)

SoftLayer Technologies do Brasil Ltda, Jundiaí (Brazil)

Responsible for customer and internal server provisioning and OS installation overseeing from racking and stacking to CAT5/6 and fiber cabling and new rack/server room preparation, as well as environmental monitoring and continuous reporting metrics. Facilities (mechanical, HVAC, electrical) inspection and prospective new facilities site surveys. Achieved total SLA compliance for customer and internal ticket response times as well as a general site cut-off in response time and human errors by co-training and mentoring newly hired co-workers along with supervisors and manager. Specifics: team work, team supervision, project management, hardware rack and stack, network and power cabling, fiber optics, operating system automated installation and troubleshooting, hardware maintenances, remote hands, Supermicro and Lenovo servers, Citrix XenServer cloud hosts and cloud servers administration, A10 load balancers, EMC storage maintenance, NetApp storage maintenance, Cisco ASR routers, Juniper MX routers, Arista switches, Fortinet firewalls

01/02/2015-30/09/2015

Operations Supervisor

Enzu Inc. Remote

Responsible for coordinating operations over 6 geographically distributed datacenters and managed to complete total elimination of a 3-year RMA processing queue.

Specifics: abuse management, helpdesk, remote team management, hardware RMA, Sharepoint internal knowledgebase maintenance, KVM cloud administration, Supermicro server quoting, ordering and assembly.



01/09/2013-09/06/2014

Operations Manager

Rackspot Lda, Remote

Position held as remote tele-worker, based in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; with frequent travel to São Paulo, Brazil and occasional trips to Lisbon, Portugal.

- Managed to negotiate contracts with telco carriers, datacenter, internet exchange points, and office vendors and day to day operations of forming the brazilian subsidiary of the Portuguese main company, prior to the main company's bankruptcy.

Specifics: Helpdesk OTRS, peering, internet exchange, internet governance community, colocation, internet carriers/telecommunications, network hardware, abuse management

01/10/2011-01/08/2013

Customer Advocate

Global Net Access, Remote

Position held as remote tele-worker, based in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.

- Responsible for customer support and sales in Portuguese as well as to keep the helpdesk clean of unanswered dead-end tickets, until the company was sold to Zayo. Achieved to reduce the average rerouting time of already-closed reopened tickets from 60h to 2h.
- Pre-sales planning of specific network setups based on Cisco Nexus 5000 and 3000 series switches platform.

Specifics: LivePerson, Kayako, Pre-Sales Engineering, Dedicated Servers, Complex Network planning, vmware vCloud, Project Management, Helpdesk

01/01/2002-31/03/2013

E-mail Server Specialist

LucaNet Sistemas Ltda, Rio de Janeiro (Brazil)

- Alternated between full-time helpdesk analyst, project consultant and implementation, and training consultant for the email-server software product (both onsite at the customer, or remotely, or training sessions in classroom), creating specifications and researching and developing bugs along with the main softwarehouse with special attention to customer advocacy.

Project Management and Implementation of small and large scale email server clusters (>100k mailboxes) and migration of email server platforms from Exchange/MailEnable/Postfix to IceWarp.

Specifics: helpdesk, knowledgebase building, remote support, Gotomeeting, Cisco webex, user and admin training, IceWarp, email infrastructure, email protocols, SMTP, POP, IMAP, MAPI, Exchange, EWS, VoIP, ActiveSync, project management, project implementation and coordination, e-mail cluster configurations (Windows and Linux), cPanel, Plesk, HELM, HostingController, FTP, SSL Certificates, mySQL, Microsoft SQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite

15/12/1999-17/02/2011

Managing Member

Self-employed web hosting enterpreneur, Remote

Home-office position based in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

- Grew from a software and web hosting service reseller business in specific niches to a fully-owned equipment and multiple carrier contracts server and cloud business until the sale of the assets and customers to a bigger company. Single-man business/company from start to end.
- Data center physical and logical migrations touching both Windows and Linux operating systems, and Cisco 6500 from/to Force10/Juniper MX/Brocade Foundry and vyatta vyOS platforms, CAT5/6 and fiber cabling.

Specifics: Windows and Linux System Administration, Plesk, cPanel, Ensim, HELM, HostingController, DotNetPanel, ColdFusion management and hosting, ASP.NET hosting and maintenance/troubleshooting, PHP hosting and troubleshooting, SmarterMail, SmarterStats, SmarterTickets, Helpdesk, contract negotiation, internet carrier turn up and troubleshooting, peering negotiations, basic BGP, ASN and IP allocation project and implementations, colocation, network (Cisco 6500, Dell Force10 S50, Foundry/Brocade), Dell, HP and Supermicro dedicated servers, virtual servers (based on vmware ESX) sales and management/administration/support.



EDUCATION AND TRAINING

16/10/2017-29/06/2018

Developer

EQF level 4

Apple Developer Academy, Napoli (Italy)

Basics of Swift programming, Application Design, Application Business, Design thinking, Agile / SCRUM methodologies, Project Management, Teamwork, Teambuilding, Problem-solving.

01/01/2000-31/12/2008

Engineering & International Relations (Abandoned)

EQF level 6

Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro (Brazil)

Engineering: switched to International relations after 1 year.

Political Science (with Sociology and Economy) course in International Relations.

Finished attending all mandatory subjects. Only needed the final term paper to graduate. Abandoned due to professional needs.

01/01/1996-31/12/1999

Electronics Technician

EQF level 4

Centro Federal de Educação Tecnológica Celso Suckow da Fonseca, Rio de Janeiro (Brazil)

High School course along with a Technical training on Basic Electricity and Discrete Electronics, including Analog Television and Radio.

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s)

Portuguese

Foreign language(s)

English
Spanish
Italian

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C2	C2	C2	C2	C2
C1	C2	C1	B2	B1
B1	C1	B1	B1	A2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user

Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

Communication skills

- good customer communication and interaction skills with customers gained through my experience as help desk and front-end customer service for years

Organisational / managerial skills

Capable of working alone or in team and under pressure; designing nonconventional solutions and using oblique strategies to solve "impossible" issues; capacity of adaptation to any company culture from "following strictly-by-the-book" to "do-it-yourself".

Job-related skills

- good command of quality control and customer satisfaction processes
- good attention to detail where and when needed
- good negotiation and passive/farmer sales skills

Digital skills

SELF-ASSESSMENT							
Information processing	Communication	Content creation	Safety	Problem- solving			
Proficient user	Proficient user	Basic user	Proficient user	Proficient user			

Digital skills - Self-assessment grid



Curriculum vitae

- 19 years of experience on the web hosting, virtual servers, dedicated servers, cloud, bandwidth and datacenter infrastructure markets, highly specialized in the most used technologies on this field

Driving licence

В

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Certifications

CertiProf DevOps Essentials Professional Certificate (January 2019) Cisco Routing & Switching Essentials - CCNA 2 (June 2018) ITIL Foundation course (uncertified)

Keywords and Technologies

Debian, Windows Server, macOS, DNS, reverse DNS, bind, domains, DHCP, SNMP, IIS, Apache, nginx, SSL, SSL Certificates, SSH, FTP, Office 365, basic Exchange, basic bash and batch scripting, debugging, TCP/IP, routing, switching, subnetting, IP address management, provisioning, email servers/flow/infrastructure, OS installation, cloud computing, customer care, ITIL, UX, data privacy, internet governance, problem-solving.

Trattamento dei dati personali

[IT]: Autorizzo il trattamento dei miei dati personali ai sensi del GDPR e del Decreto Legislativo 30 giugno 2003, n. 196 "Codice in materia di protezione dei dati personali". [EN]: In compliance with the EU GDPR and Italian Legislative Decree no. 196 dated 30/06/2003, I hereby authorize the recipient of this document to use and process my personal details for the purpose of recruiting and selecting staff and I confirm to be informed of my rights in accordance to art. 7 of the above mentioned Decree.